<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wd's blog (Posts about film)</title><link>https://fpghwd.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://fpghwd.github.io/categories/film.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:ggwdwhu@gmail.com"&gt;suzumiya natsuhi&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 12:23:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>《第六感生死缘》</title><link>https://fpghwd.github.io/posts/di-liu-gan-sheng-si-yuan/</link><dc:creator>suzumiya natsuhi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Susan 在飞机上听父亲 William 说：
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
William: Do you love Drew?
Susan: You mean, like you loved Mom?
William: Forget about me and Mom. Are you gonna marry him?
Susan: (…)
William: Oh, come on.
Susan: I’m probably
William: Listen, I’m crazy about the guy. He’s smart. He’s aggressive. He could carry Parrish Communications into the 21st century and me along with it.
Susan: Mm-hmm, So, what’s wrong with that?
William: That’s for me. I’m talking about you. It’s not what you say about Drew. It’s what you don’t say.
Susan: Maybe you’re not listening.
William: Oh, yes I am. Give him whatever he wants. There’s not an ounce of excitement, not a whisper of a thrill. And this relationship has all the passion of a pair of titmice. I want you to get swept away out there. I want you to levitate. I want you to … sing with rapture and dance like a dervish.
Susan: (Smiling)Oh, that’s all.
William: Yeah. Be deliriously happy, or at least leave yourself open to be.
Susan: Okay. “Be deliriously happy.” I shall, uh, I shall do my utmost.
William: I know it’s a cornball thing. But love is passion, obsession, someone you can’t live without. (…) I say, fall head over heels. Find someone you can love like crazy and who will love you the same way back. How do you find him? Well, you forget your head, and you listen to your heart. And I’m not hearing any heart. ’Cause the truth is, honey, there’s no sense living your life without this. To make the journey and not fall deeply in love, well, you haven’t lived a life at all. But you have to try. ’cause if you haven’t tried, you haven’t lived.
Susan: Bravo!
William: Oh, you’re tough.
Susan: I’m sorry. Okay. Give it to me again, but the short version this time.
William: Okay. Stay open. Who knows? Lighting could strike.
Susan: (Smiling)
William: Yeah?
Susan: Yeah.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
感觉开头就已经讲完故事了，对于我来说。
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>film</category><guid>https://fpghwd.github.io/posts/di-liu-gan-sheng-si-yuan/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 04:22:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>《狗镇》</title><link>https://fpghwd.github.io/posts/kan-wan-dian-ying-gou-zhen-de-yi-dian-xiang-fa/</link><dc:creator>suzumiya natsuhi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Grace 重新见到父亲时，父亲说了以下的话：
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
你错了，他们犯下的错误，只是因为他们在服从自己的本性。原谅，宽恕，是在纵容罪恶。你要宽恕他们，原谅他们，才是真正的傲慢。因为只有上帝才有资格去宽恕人类的罪责，去原谅他们的错误。当你要原谅所有有罪之人的时候，就是在傲慢地将自己比肩上帝。但你却指责我，说我傲慢。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
其实在中国也有这样的表述：“以德报怨，何以报德？”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>film</category><guid>https://fpghwd.github.io/posts/kan-wan-dian-ying-gou-zhen-de-yi-dian-xiang-fa/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 07:39:45 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>